Hello friends, welcome to Smart Wealth
Advisors. Today, updates of ICSE potential have
come. We will not say results, but updates.
So, on December 8th, people updated their
old presentation
and perhaps it was the result of that that
today the stock also shot up to 3. And right now, I
see that this means there is amazing
potential. I keep telling some stocks
that this is a 100 billion dollar
market cap opportunity, so
this is one of them. Okay, again, disclaimer, I own
ICSE potential only in my
portfolio and I am not a SEBI advisor,
so for all your buy and sell, take the help of
your advisor. Okay,
so we will discuss
what is there in the updates in the results
which is very important.
Okay, so before the results, we will tell you two or
three important factors,
what is VNB? It is a
little different from the insurance business,
not everyone can read it. Okay, so the three
important factors which are VNB are the value of
So what is the value of a new business,
the present value of the
future earnings? This is a figure,
what can a figure do today, for example, the
premium that we are getting, for
example, suppose you have taken an endowment policy, then
how much profit can it make on that, can we
calculate a figure, can we
calculate the future value, okay, so it should
reflect the additional earnings
expected to be generated through the new
policy. So,
whatever new policies are coming from new policies, if
their margin is high, if the VNB
margin is high, okay, then the profit
that is going to be made, if the new policy is being issued, then the
profit is going to be very high, that is, quite high.
Then
what is the annual premium, annual premium means the sum
of the total value of regular and recurring
premium, okay, whatever the old regular and
recurring premium is, plus 10 percent of the
new single premium, okay, single
premium only, okay,
its 10 percent only is taken in it, then
retail weighted  What is it again, total premium
collected through retail policies, only
division policies, not group
policies, retail dec,
these three are very important
factors to
see the results of any insurance company,
okay, so let's directly go to new
business, this is very important, it is extremely important
that new business means new
business is very high for any insurance company, it
means that now they are getting more new
customers, okay, the same customer
can buy another policy, but more new customers are
coming, okay, then the new business
premium has
grown by 32.1%, the AP is big, the VNB margin is
running very solid, very solid,
okay, this is amazing, this is the most important,
you see the BNB margin alone,
you compare everyone, whose BNB margin is the
best, that is most important
and also how well someone is doing, okay, if
you look at any brand, like small
insurance companies,
their consistency is very  Decreasing persistence means
how many people came back, how many people came back, like
we bought a policy,
paid its premium this year, next year, am I coming back to pay
my premium or not,
okay, so persistence
is calculated for many months, 13 months, but the latest one is
at 82, which means that the brand
value of your ICC potential is increasing,
okay, so two, two, two are very important, I do
n't want to understand it so much, two, two, it is very
important that persistence is increasing, which
means brand value is increasing, more and
more people are coming for the policy, BNB
margin is good, which means the margins are good in whatever new policy is being launched,
why those margins are good, I will
tell you later, okay, mostly sold
protection business, okay, now one, two and a
very important factor comes channel
wise, so whatever channel it is, like channel one
on any channel, first the dependency should be less,
this is important, okay, so now we will
see, the biggest channel wise
in production, their bank's insurance and
agency, one of the strongest I can say
bank  Insurance especially because ICICI Bank sells insurance
solely because ICICI Bank
sells insurance, right after that these people keep doing their business
from bank to RBL,
bank sells insurance from there, okay, there is an
agency which are their agents, they
sell through the agency, okay
now see here one important
thing to see is that if we compare 2019 and 2020,
okay, ULIP, ULIP should keep going
down a little bit, okay, but even today
in India, the insurance companies,
private insurance companies, are very much
dependent on ULIP, okay, or not, it is a bad idea, okay,
but a lot of money is lost from this,
it is very good
that ULIP keeps decreasing in the total business,
okay, so see here also ULIP has decreased,
here also it has decreased, here also it has decreased, that means
overall ULIP is decreasing, okay
because ULIP is not a good business,
okay for any insurance company, it is a
very good thing,
second comes the persistence, which I was talking about,
persistence is a  It is also
one of the biggest parameters for a life insurance company.
It tells
how many of your old customers are coming back
because if your old ones don't come back then
you will have to work very hard to attract new customers. So, are
you able to manage the old customers that are building up? Whether the old
policies are getting renewed or not is a
very important
fact.
Now let's come to the next one. Let's go to the
screener here. So, this is what
I saw today. Look, I have put in my
presentation, this is today's presentation. If you want to
study any other place, then
go to that now. But overall, the
growth that I am seeing, mostly the
growth of new business, I was checking whether
it is coming in tremendously or not. This is
very important. It has come in tremendously. So,
according to me, now the company is
slowly coming back on track. It is
coming back on track. Now, I mean,
why insurance? I will not talk about
how the insurance business is.
In insurance, we already know that it is
so solid, I mean, for decades.  There
is a business for me, okay, now why do
I give a lot of importance to both ICC Potential and HDFC Life,
exclude any agency, there is
SBI also, but generally I do
not touch PSC, okay, so I have
HDFC Life, ICC Potential in my account
portfolio, the biggest power of both the companies is their
subsidiaries, okay, like
ADC has AC Bank, such as IC,
ICICI Bank, their network is
very strong, ICC Security
helps them, IC Lombard helps them, they
all mine each other's data,
so they have like they have millions
and millions of customers to mine, okay, this becomes
very important, okay, so the
overall results have been quite good and